Pietro Torrico Escobar, Full Stack Developer

+591 69531998, torricopietro@gmail.com

LINKS

LinkedIn, GitHub, Portfolio

PROFILE

Full Stack Developer with 3 years of experience working with React, Next.js, Angular, Nodejs, JavaScript, Typescript, NestJs, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, HTML, and CSS to deliver exceptional user experiences. Expert in contributing to highly collaborative work environments, findingsolutions, and ensuring customer satisfaction.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Agu 2021 — Present

Full Stack Developer, Loop Corporation

Cochabamba, Bolivia

Who gives a crap [USA]

- Optimized the checkout page by automatically autofilling fields through API connections, reducing the dropout rate by 7%.
- Developed the client admin panel, migrating from a React SPA to a Next.js application, improving performance through server-side rendering.
- Created a new shopping cart, reducing cart abandonment by improving UX and implementing a pop-up system.

Tech Stack:

React, Liquid, Shopify, Typescript, Styled Components, Apollo graphql, Redux, Nextjs, Webpack

Acceso 360 [Spain]

- Developed an integrated system for management, collection, and automated content delivery and news
 by creating a SPA with React using Domain Driven Design, used by over 300 marketing agencies, news
 agencies, content agencies, and governments.
- Optimized the creation of advanced search for news collection, improving quality and match of collected news by implementing Lucene syntax validation.
- Developed the design system using React, Tailwind, StoryBook, and Vitest, increasing development team
 productivity through reusable components.
- Implemented unit tests using Vitest, doubling the number of unit tests in the application, reducing bugs and improving code quality.

Tech Stack:

React, Tailwind, Zustand, Tankstackquery, Typescript, StoryBook, Docker, API Rest, Vitest ,DDD

Awtu Ecommerce

- Contributed to the development of a CMS designed for e-commerce management, implementing the frontend with Angular for an intuitive and efficient interface.
- Designed the MongoDB database, ensuring support for multiple entities and optimizing data organization.
- Optimized communication between microservices, significantly reducing response times and eliminating unnecessary processes, improving system efficiency.

Tech Stack:

Angular, Apollo Ang., Typescript, Tailwind, Nodejs, Graphql, Express, Rabbitmq, MongoDB, Docker.

Jul 2024 — Present

Front End Developer, DeltaX

Santa Cruz, Bolivia

- Designed and integrated Google Maps API to display real-time truck locations, enhancing fleet management capabilities and user experience.
- Improved the frontend permissions system for a SaaS platform, ensuring dynamic functionality based on the specific requirements of each company.
- Redesigned and enhanced the user interface and experience by creating reusable, adaptable components.

Tech Stack:

React, Material UI, Redux, Typescript, API Res, React Google Maps

Aug 2023 — F	eb 20)24
--------------	-------	-----

Front End Developer, Alhasoft (Freelancer)

La Paz, Bolivia

- Developed a real estate investment platform with Next.js, leveraging its server-side rendering capabilities for SEO optimization, successfully raising over \$10,000 on the first day of launch.
- Integrated a payment gateway, allowing users to utilize more than 5 payment methods by connecting to the "PagosNet" API.
- Implemented user validation and restriction through an authentication system, account validation, and password recovery.
- Utilized Web3 to interact with the blockchain and generate smart contracts.

Tech Stack:

React, NextJs, Tailwind, Redux, Typescript, API Rest

EDUCATION

Jan 2022 — Dec 2024	Bachelor's Degree in Systems Engineering, Universidad Adventista de Bolivia (UAB)	Cochabamba
Jan 2018 — Dec 2021	Technical Superior in Computer Systems, ICEPAL Technical Institute	Cochabamba
Jan 2020 — Dec 2023	Bachelor's Degree in Commercial Engineering, University Mayor de San Simón	Cochabamba

LANGUAGES

- Spanish Native
- English B2